lan Del Giudice

SKILLS

Javascript – Native JS & ESNext. React & JS frameworks, Typescript. Also some nodeJS, Angular, Vercel & GraphQL. 10 years JS experience.

WordPress – Enterprise WordPress theme & plugin development, custom Gutenberg blocks, Headless WP, and theme.json. 15 years PHP experience.

Styles – Organized, optimized and performant CSS. PostCSS & SCSS preprocessors, Webpack & npm.

HTML – Semantic, WCAG accessible markup. JSX/PHP/Liquid template components.

Design – Implementing Figma design mock-ups. Skilled with Illustrator, SVGs, and Photoshop.

Codebase Admin – Version control with Git. Code standards & review, testing, linters, and deployments.

Project Leadership – Technical architecture, project scope & estimate docs, team & client collaboration.

ABOUT

I'm a Brooklyn based full-stack web developer, originally from Providence, RI, where I began my career in 2009. With 11 years experience working remotely with WordPress VIP partner agencies, I am interested in joining a remote team for a full-time senior front-end or full stack developer role.

EXPERIENCE

10up, Inc.

Front-End Engineer, Feb 2019 - Nov 2023

Led project teams at a fully-distributed WordPress VIP agency. As a senior front-end engineer I regularly worked with WP plugins & themes, React, NextJS, TypeScript, custom Gutenberg Blocks, and Headless WP to deliver high quality and fully customized web applications for enterprise clients with tight timelines and budgets, while contributing to internal tooling.

Alley Interactive

UX Developer, Dec 2014 - Jun 2018

Collaborated with a remote scrum/agile team to build and maintain enterprise-scale themes & plugins for a WordPress VIP partner agency. As a project tech lead, we utilized CSS Preprocessors, ES6, Webpack, React, Angular, and rapid in-browser prototyping.

Oomph, Inc.

Front-End Developer, Jul 2012 - Feb 2014

Worked with different project teams at a WordPress VIP partner agency. Tasks involved custom theme & plugin development for WordPress and Drupal sites.

eMagine Communications

Website Maintenance, Mar 2010 - Mar 2012

Responsible for servicing client requests for website updates, improvements, and providing support for WordPress, Joomla, and .NET projects.

EDUCATION

Rhode Island College

*Graphic Communications, Jan 2008 – Jan 2010*Pursued a BA in Graphic Communications. Course work included graphic design, prepress layouts & screens, web development, and media literacy.